The last snake we're going to look at today is the sand boa.
This is an anytheristic sand boa meaning it lacks the red pigmentation.
That's why it is a black and white sand boa.
Usually they are an orangish red and black.
This is a female sand boa.
Sand boas are one of the few snakes where you can actually tell the sex by dimorphism which means they have, both sexes have different characteristics.
The sand boas, the females have a much shorter fatter tail than the males do.
The males have a longer tail section.
Interesting things about the sand boas, the sand boas do live most of their lives underground.
If you look at the shape of the head it has an incline on it.
It's what we like to call shovel head so it's flat on the bottom here and it goes slightly inclined up to the top and that's to help them burrow down.
If you ever see them in action they really do, they just slide right in the dirt like it's water and disappear right away.
These guys max out at about two to three feet.
They don't get very big.
They stay nice and small.
They're usually pretty well mannered as well.
They're easy to keep.
They're a desert species living in a sandy dirt kind of substrate.
You can see he's sniffing around with his little tongue checking everything out making sure that there's nothing that's going to eat him or that he can eat.
This is a pretty typical patterning for a sand boa.
Blotches of black and the coloration between.
The splotches can be bigger or smaller depending on the sand boa.
Sometimes you get a little bit of banding though it's relatively rare.
There are a couple of different species of sand boas.
There's Tanzanian sand boas, Kenyan sand boas, rough scaled sand boas.
So not all sand boas are the same.
There's various differences between the species such as eye placement, shape and feel of the scales and things like that, but more often than not what you will see in a pet store is going to be a Kenyan sand boa because that is the most popular species and most readily available.